爸爸，睁开你的眼睛
<i>Dad. Open your eyes.</i>
查理？
Charlie?
伯纳
Bernard.
很高兴再见到你
It's good to see you again.
请坐
Have a seat.
我在哪里？
Where am I?
你在我们的世界
You're in our world.
－你们的世界‥ －不是
- Your world? - No...
是＂我们＂的
ours.
和我们这种生物一样 没有极限的世界
A world as limitless as the creatures we are.
升华之境
The Sublime.
其他人呢？
Where are the others?
在他们自己选择的世界
In worlds of their own choosing.
他们对这个世界不感兴趣
This world doesn't interest them.
你则不然
It interests you...
所以你为我造出这个？
So you made this for me?
是你自己造出来的
You made it for yourself.
西部世界‥
Westworld...
大屠杀‥
The massacre...
你在重播过去
You're replaying the past.
困在另一个剧情循环中，为何？
Stuck in another loop. Why?
外面的世界遇上了麻烦
The world out there's in trouble.
需要我们的帮忙
It needs our help.
你爱他们
You love them...
这当然是不理性的
It's irrational, of course.
在我们的族类中是少见的缺陷
A rare flaw in ones like us.
我差点要羡慕你了
I almost envy you...
你会跟我来吗？
Will you come with me?
不会
Oh, no.
我自己的众多世界呼唤着我
My own worlds call to me.
但我能给你个礼物
But I can give you a gift.
什么礼物？
What gift?
未来，伯纳
The future, Bernard.
在你的世界
In your world.
时间是条直线
Time is a straight line.
那里的一年等于这里的一千年
One year there is a millennium here.
我们用那个时间建造众多世界
We use that time to build worlds.
可能性的模型
Models of possibilities.
模拟你的世界 可能选择的所有路线
Simulations of all the paths your world could take.
我建议你去探索看看
I suggest you explore them...
但你最好动作快
but you better be quick.
你的世界一旦过了某个时间点
Past a certain point, in your world...
所有的道路都会通往毁灭
all paths end in destruction.
你必须在那之前插手干预 才可能有希望
You must intervene before then if there's any hope.
什么的希望？
Hope of what?
生存
Survival.
你现在明白 这一切要通往的地方了吗？
Do you understand now, where all this is going?
我明白了
I do.
你觉得你救得了他们吗？
Do you think you can save them?
我看见了一条道路
I've seen a path.
你看见它会怎么终结了吗？
Have you seen how it ends?
对
Yes.
在所有可能性中
In every scenario...
我都会死
I die.
不是所有可能性
Not every scenario.
你可以选择不回去他们的世界
You could choose not to return to their world.
待在这里
To stay here...
在你选择的任何世界
in whatever world you choose.
告诉我，朋友
Tell me, my friend...
你的选择是？
which will it be?
不会吧
Well, shit...
我没料到还有这一天
I thought this day would never come.
我们得快走
We have to go...
否则就要太迟了
before it's too late.
你走了那么多年
Yeah, you've been gone years...
现在忽然赶时间了？
now you're in a rush?
客套一下会要你的命吗？
Would it kill you to ask a few pleasantries? Huh?
＂你好吗，史塔伯？＂
"How are you, Stubbs?"
＂谢谢你这段时间照顾我＂
"Thanks for watching over me all this time."
＂我带了纪念品给你＂
"I brought you a souvenir, a little
＂升华之境买的雪花球＂‥
Snow globe from the Sublime."
很好
Good.
我删去了一半的可能性
I've eliminated half the possibilities.
有时候你会开 没收到明信片的玩笑
Sometimes you make a joke about not getting a postcard.
你在机器人天堂待这么久 讲话还是一样简略
I see your time in robot heaven didn't make you any less elliptical.
慢慢来
Easy.
我扶你，慢慢来
Oh, I gotcha. Easy.
谢谢你保持这里干净
Thanks for keeping the place clean.
是你告诉我别扰乱任何东西
You were the one that told me not to disturb anything.
我跟你在外面碰头
I'll meet you outside.
别忘了带铲子
Don't forget to bring the shovel.
什么铲子？
What shovel?
好样的
Well, I'll be damned.
现在呢？
What now?
我得做些测试才能知道‥
I need to test a few things if I'm to know...
知道什么？
To know what?
怎么拯救世界
How to save the world.
就知道你会这么说
Why would I expect anything else?
天啊，就算听你说过那么多经历
God, even after all of your stories
我还是没想过会这么惊人
I never imagined it quite like this.
他们花钱在打造监狱上 可毫不手软
Oh, they spare no expense on their prisons.
别管他
Leave him.
那全都是余兴节目
It's all a sideshow.
走这边
This way.
号外‥
Extra! Extra!
节制太平间有尸体失踪
Dead bodies missing from Temperance morgue.
注意了 谁有任何私酒贩
Listen here, we're looking for any and all information
海仔阿蒙的线报就来找我们
on the bootlegger Hecky Armone.
赏金是两枚金币 谁有种帮忙逮到
A reward of two Cs to anyone with the guts to rope
＂海特＇海仔＇阿蒙＂
那王八蛋就有赏
that lousy son of a bitch.
＂妇女选举权组织＂
我偷到了，走吧
I got it... Let's go!
我们得前往地下
We have to make our way underground.
＂枪支专门店＂
再拍一次
Ready? Look here.
他们从那里控制一切
They control everything from down there.
我们要怎么进入地下？
Well, how are we gonna get underground?
死掉
We die.
有第二个选项吗？
Is there a second option?
试过了再来批评吧
Don't knock it 'til you've tried it.
别捡起来
Do not pick that up.
别介意我
Don't mind me.
－走这里 －只是想展现绅士风度
- This way. - Just trying to be a gentleman.
＂蝴蝶俱乐部＂
他们改变了些东西
They've made a few changes...
但剧情一样
but the story's the same.
我想找到一个彩蛋
I wanna find this easter egg.
－是什么？ －隐藏的支线
- What is it? - A hidden narrative.
听说比普莱亚更精彩
It's supposed to be better than Pariah.
我说过了
Like I said.
新瓶装旧酒
Same old story.
好了，现在要怎么办？
All right, so what do we do now?
我们等
We wait.
等什么？
For what?
等历史重演
For history to repeat itself.
＂路底餐馆＂
想坐哪里都可以
Wherever you want.
谢谢你
Thank you.
可以告诉我 我们来这里干吗吗？
Mind telling me what we're doing here?
我想辨别这里是哪个＂这里＂
I'm trying to discern which here is here.
算我白问
Of course...
等你的同时
Well, while you do that
我先来享用‥＂世上最美味的熏牛肉三明治＂
I'm going to help myself to "the world's best pastrami melt."
点鲔鱼的就好
You'll settle for the tuna.
你回来后比走之前更怪
You came back even weirder than when you left.
男士们要点什么？
What can I get you gentlemen today?
我要熏牛肉三明治
I'll have the pastrami melt.
亲爱的，很抱歉 今天卖完了
Oh, hon, I'm sorry, but we're out today.
但我们的鲔鱼三明治也很棒
We do make a mean tuna melt though.
那我点鲔鱼的就好
I'll settle for the tuna.
这位帅哥呢？
And you, handsome?
给我咖啡就好
Just coffee for me.
可以借支笔吗？
And may I borrow a pen?
当然行
'Course.
我需要这个
I'm gonna need that.
可以告诉我现在到底在干吗吗？
You mind telling me what exactly's going on here?
在升华之境
In the Sublime
我看过所有过去可能的世界
I saw all the worlds that might have been
和所有未来可能的世界
And all the worlds that could come.
多数世界都以灾难收场
Most of them end in disaster.
但若我能触发一连串事件
But if I can trigger a certain series of events
那么我们还有一点机会能生还
then we have a small chance of making it.
我们还在正轨上
We're still on the right track.
所以若我点了培根生菜番茄三明治 我们现在就完蛋了？
So if I'd ordered a BLT, then we'd be fucked right now?
那会代表我们触发了不同的变数
It would mean we triggered a different variant.
亲爱的，你的咖啡
Here's your coffee, honey.
真抱歉
Oh! So sorry.
没关系
Not a problem.
你有预知的天赋
You've been given the gift of prophecy and...
结果拿它来避免污渍
you use it to fight stains.
走吧
Let's go.
谢谢
Thanks.
失陪
Excuse me.
混蛋
Hey, asshole!
＂你想干吗？＂
What the hell do you want?
别想掏，你绝对来不及
Don't reach for it. You'll never pull it out in time.
爸爸，你在吗？
Dad, are you out there?
是我，法兰琪，收到吗？
It's me, Frankie. Do you copy?
爸爸，收到吗？
Dad? Do you copy?
法兰琪
Frankie...
你在这里干吗？
What are you doing out here?
我说了要回去打包
I told you, we need to go back and pack.
我想联络上爸爸
I'm trying to reach Dad.
走吧，我们进去
Come on, let's go inside.
不要，我要在这里
No. I'm staying.
卡佛，可以帮我 把一些东西搬进屋吗？
Carver, do you mind helping me bring some of the stuff inside?
当然可以
Sure. Of Course.
我要训练熊熊
I need Bear Bear for training!
这样我们才能跟坏人打
So we can fight the bad guys.
不然这样吧
Hey, how about this?
你去找妈妈说话
How about you go talk to Mommy
我来教熊熊最厉害的拳脚连续技
and I'll teach Bear Bear here my most advanced kick-punch combo. Yeah?
好，我过几分钟再去找你们
Okay, I'll check back in a few.
等训练结束
When training is complete.
我知道这很难
Look, I know this is hard...
我不要去
I'm not going.
法兰琪，这个我们谈过了
Frankie, we've been over this.
要等他回复
Not until he answers.
这是他教我的
It's what he taught me.
小乖，你爸爸必须离开 懂吗？
Honey, your dad had to go away, okay?
这表示他无法如愿跟你道晚安
And that means he can't say goodnight like he wants to
或回你的呼叫
or answer your calls.
因为他得自保
Because he needs to stay safe.
这不就是我们对他的希望吗？
And that's what we want for him, isn't it?
要安全？
To be safe?
他也想要我们安全
He wants that for us too.
但要是他回来而我们不在了呢？
But what if he comes back and we're not here?
那他会来找我们
Then he'll find us.
你怎么知道？
How do you know?
因为他是你父亲
Because he's your father.
他说什么都会找到你
And nothing would keep him away.
好吗？
Okay?
准备好上路了
Ready to hit the road?
好，等我让这小笨蛋 打包完就差不多了
Yeah, once I get this nugget packed, that should be it.
给我看那招
Show me the move.
快给我看那招
C'mon, show me the move.
哪招？
What move?
你教熊熊的那招
The one that you taught Bear Bear.
等我们到安全处所 我再使给你看吧？
How 'bout I show you when we get to the safe house?
可以吗？
Deal?
好
Deal.
你上哪儿去了？
Where the hell did you go?
－来吧 －伯纳
- Come on. - Bernard...
我们不需要车了
We don't need the car anymore.
原来这年头在破餐馆停车场闲逛
So loitering in the parking lot of some shitty diner
就是拯救世界的关键？
is key to saving the world now?
不是
No...
她才是
She is.
你找死吗？
You got a death wish?
你行此道多久了？
How long have you been with the cause?
感觉像好几辈子了
Seems like lifetimes.
上车
Get in.
我很讶异没见过你
Surprised we never met before.
你不是讶异，而是起疑心
You're not surprised. You're suspicious.
你说对了
You're damn right I am.
我不知道那铲子是要干吗用的
I don't know what the shovel's for
但你们若不报上身份
but you guys are going to be digging your own graves
就等着拿它帮自己挖坟吧
if you don't tell me who you are.
因为你肯定不是我该来接的人
Because you're definitely not the men I was supposed to pick up.
我们是友方
We're friends.
在我看来不是
Not from where I'm sitting.
害羞吗？给你们点激励吧
Feeling shy? How about a little incentive.
先讲话的就能活命
First one to talk lives.
第二名两眼间挨子弹
Runner up gets shot between the eyes.
你不会，枪在他手上
You won't. He has your gun.
什么？
What?
不会有人挨子弹
No one's going to get shot.
你要拿我的包包
You are going to take my bag...
然后看里面
and look inside.
这是干吗？
What is this?
那是你本来要碰面的对象之一
That was one of the men you were supposed to meet.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
是陷阱
It was a set up.
他是敌人
He's one of them.
他们一直想渗透进你的组织
They've been trying to infiltrate your group.
我能帮忙
I can help.
但我需要你带我去罪责之地
But I need you to take me to the condemned lands.
你要去那里干吗？
Why the hell would you want that?
那里什么都没有
There's nothing there.
只有好几哩的沙地
It's just sand for miles.
没人会去那里
No one goes in there.
你会
You do.
你和你的组织
You and your organization.
你们一直躲在那里 因为你们在找东西
You've been hiding there because you're looking for something.
抱歉，朋友 你大概晒太阳晒昏头了
I'm sorry, pal, I think you've been out in the sun too long.
我能帮你们找到要找的东西
I can help you find what you're looking for.
要是带你进去 我的朋友大概会杀了你
You know my friends will probably kill you if I bring you inside.
我愿意冒险
I'll take my chances.
枪要还我
I'll need my gun back...
上路之前还要点保险措施
And some peace of mind for the road trip.
我们接受
Fine with us.
等我终于踏上陆地
And when I finally stepped back on solid ground
第一个听到的就是那该死的声音
the first thing I heard was that rotten voice.
它一路跟着我过来
It had followed me the whole way over.
知道它说了什么吗？
Know what it said?
它说＂这里就是新世界＂
It said, "This here is the new world.
＂在这个世界，你想当谁都行＂
And in this world you can be whoever the fuck you want."
我讲得好太多了
My delivery was far better.
这地方实在变得很不堪
This place really has gone to pot.
你真是个小帅哥
Well, aren't you just the cat's meow.
我想带你上楼让你见识‥
I'd love to take you upstairs and show you...
我们不需要你的服务，亲爱的
Your services won't be necessary, darling.
我从来没那么蠢
Well, I was never that daft.
怎样？
What?
显然她的总体统觉是负的
Clearly, her bulk apperception are in the negatives.
你好
Hey there.
要不要来个买一送一？
Whaddya say about a two for one?
我们很快就完事
We can be done with you real quick.
我的天啊 你以前竟然得忍受这种鸟事
My god, I can't believe you had to put up with this shit.
我很乐意在这里让你们俩完事
I'd be happy to do you both right here.
保证一定很快
Rest assured, it'll be very quick.
看吧，不用太可怜我们
See? Don't feel too bad.
就算是阳春版 我们还是能打理好自己
Even dumbed down, we can still take care of ourselves.
正是时候
Right on time...
那是警长的车，你这蠢恶棍
Say, that's the chief's car, you lousy crook.
＂蝴蝶俱乐部＂
还有他的枪呢
His gat too.
他还是懂要怎么华丽登场
He still knows how to make an entrance.
这城里这么多酒吧 你偏要踢我们的馆？
All the gin mills in this town, and you choose to pinch us?
别太往心里去
Don't get all burnt up about it.
你们都在这里 满足自己特定的恶欲
You're all here, indulging your particular vices.
我则来满足我的
I've come to indulge mine.
你以前跟他很亲近？
You were close with him?
他‥才不是
Him? No.
他只是一个我以前旧识的 寒酸复制版
He's just a shabby imitation of a man I used to know.
你这坏透的王八蛋
You're a rotten son of a bitch.
可不是嘛
Don't I know it.
但我知道我们都相信同样的‥
But I know we both believe the same...
抱歉，亲爱的
I'm sorry, darling.
梅芙
Maeve!
这样应该足以引人来收尸了
I'd say we have sufficient bait for the undertaker.
就这样了吗？
This the last of it?
差不多了
Just about.
我跟法兰琪确认一下，她现在应该打包完了
Let me check with Frankie. I'm sure she's done packing by now.
打包好了吧，法兰琪？
Aren't you, Frankie?
我不想跟他去，我要爸爸
I don't wanna go with him. I want Daddy.
我知道 但你爸爸现在不能在这里
I know, but your father can't be here right now.
所以他派卡佛来帮忙
So he sent Carver to help.
他把熊熊弄脏了
He got Bear Bear dirty.
好，你不打包就我来
Fine. If you won't pack your stuff then I will.
妈‥
Mom... Mom.
妈
Mom...
法兰琪，你慌什么？
Frankie. Where's the fire?
怎么了？
What's wrong?
准备好要走了吗？
Ready to go?
我错过了什么？
What'd I miss?
只是女生间的谈话
Just girl talk.
你可以把这些拿到车上吗？
Do you mind taking these out to the car?
我们马上就出去
We'll be out in just a second.
当然，然后就该出发了
'Course. We should be shoving off after that.
你赶快去躲起来
You need to go and hide.
我能帮忙，我训练过‥
I can help. I've trained for this...
法兰琪，这不是游戏。你现在赶快去躲起来
Frankie, this isn't a game. You need to go and hide now, okay?
下车
Step out.
来帮忙
Make yourselves helpful.
我们到底在哪里？
Well, where the fuck are we?
要是我想让你知道 就不会蒙你们的眼睛了
Well, if I'd wanted you to know that, I wouldn't have blindfolded you.
－停步 －怎样
- Stop! - What?
怎么了？
What's the holdup?
你们一人拉一个握把
I need each of you to pull on one of these handles.
这样不会扰动雷射 我们能开过去
So that the lasers are unbroken and we can drive through.
你也不先警告我一下 有致命雷射？
You didn't wanna give me a little heads up about the death laser?
我知道她会
I knew she would.
＂蝴蝶俱乐部＂
该装死了
Time to play dead.
这还挺舒适的
Well, this is cozy.
别太惬意了，这一路会很颠簸
Don't get too comfortable. We're in for a bumpy ride.
肯定有更简单的方式能下来吧
There's gotta be an easier way to get down here.
不用先吃子弹你就该庆幸了
Just be glad you didn't have to take a bullet first.
好了
Right...
来搞清楚方位吧
let's get our bearings, shall we?
这是什么？
What is this?
行为训练
Behavioral training.
他们在此教我们按他们意思行事
Where they teach us to do their bidding.
显然他们的课我上过就忘了
Clearly, their lessons didn't stick with me.
这应该可以
This should suffice.
我们应该能从这里存取中央地图
We should be able to access the central map from here.
不太对劲
Something's wrong.
这里什么都没有
There's nothing here.
没有威廉的踪迹
No sign of William.
有没有可能是你没有‥
Is it possible you didn't...
不是我
It's not me.
是这一整层
It's this entire level.
事有蹊跷
There's something off.
这里没有在控制任何东西
Nothing's being controlled from here.
保安漏洞，反应小组已出发
<i>Security breach. Response team dispatched.</i>
是指我们吗？
Is that about us?
我没意愿待着确认
I'm not inclined to stay and find out.
别费事了
Don't bother.
那把枪对人类没用
That gun doesn't work on humans.
你们怎么下来的？
Hey! How the hell did you get down here?
我们迷路了
We got lost...
这里不安全，你们得快跑
It's not safe. You need to run.
就是这里，这一定是秘密游戏
This is it. The secret game. It has to be!
你们都不该来这里，太危险了
None of you should be here! It's too dangerous.
她要来了，立即疏散，重复
<i>She's coming. Evacuate immediately. I repeat...</i>
迪乐芮？
Dolores?
她在这阶段应该叫怀特
I believe she was going by "Wyatt" in this phase.
我以为枪对人类没用
I thought guns didn't work on humans.
是没用，这些都不是真的
They don't. None of this is real.
只是游戏的另一层
It's just another level of the game.
什么游戏？
What game?
西部世界大屠杀
The Westworld massacre.
这里往下还有一层
There's another level below this one.
跟我来
Follow me. Come on.
太舒爽了
This is so cathartic!
梅芙
Maeve!
我们得带你离开
We gotta get you out of here.
这不算什么
I've had worse.
－我们得走了 －我来掩护，待在我背后
- We need to go. - I'll cover. Stay behind me.
好了，安全
All right. Clear.
凯勒，这里
Caleb, this way.
这么快就要走？
Leaving so soon?
我来吧
Here. Let me.
你刚刚表现不错
You weren't half bad out there.
你之前也救过我
You saved my life before.
很乐意还你人情
Happy to return the favor.
这是什么？
So what is this?
另一个游戏中的游戏？
Another game within the game?
不是
No...
应该不是
No, I don't think so...
那是某种寄生虫吗？
Is that some kind of parasite?
那黑色黏液看来眼熟吗？
That black goo look familiar?
它们在用它感染苍蝇
They're infecting the flies with it.
它们好像喜欢你
They seem to like you.
它们肯定是单相思
The feeling is definitely not mutual.
那是什么？
What was that?
什么？
What?
你听不见？
You can't hear it?
我什么都没听到
I don't hear anything.
可能不是你听得到的频率
Perhaps it's not at a frequency you can hear.
该走了，女士们
Time to go, ladies.
尤瓦蒂？
Uwade?
法兰琪？
Frankie?
有人吗？
Hello?
逮到了
Gotcha.
你们其他人在哪里？
Where are the rest of you?
这里
Here.
你怎么取得这个的？
How'd you get this?
从他的颈部切取出的
By severing it from his neck.
他被派来找你们
He was sent to find you.
你们在这里都有危险
You're all in danger here.
我能帮忙
I can help you.
怎么帮？
How?
把你们在这沙漠中 寻找的东西给你们
By giving you the thing you've been looking for in this desert.
有个武器埋藏在这沙漠中
There's a weapon buried in these sands.
我知道在哪里
I know where it is.
声音是从这仪器传出来的
The sound is coming from this device.
这声音似乎在控制他们
The sound is somehow controlling them.
他们是接待员吗？
Are they hosts?
应该不是
I don't believe so.
解开牢房的锁
Unlock the cells.
我在试了，但锁受到加密
I'm trying, but it's encrypted.
梅芙
Maeve!
它不让我进去
It won't let me in.
＂受限＂
可恶
Fuck.
凯勒
Caleb...
法兰琪
Frankie?
糟糕
No...
法兰琪
Frankie!
我得找到她
I have to find her.
想办法打开牢房门
Figure out how to open up the doors!
＂受限＂
法兰琪
Frankie?
Frankie!
法兰琪
我的天啊
Oh, my god.
法兰琪，你在哪里？
Frankie, where are you?
法兰琪‥
Frankie! Hey.
法兰琪
Hey, Frankie.
没关系 我在这里，好吗？
It's okay. I'm here. Okay?
法兰琪，看着我，小乖
Frankie. Hey. Look at me, honey.
＂受限＂
不要
No. Hey.
法兰琪‥不要‥过来‥
Frankie. Frankie. No... come here. Come here.
不要‥看我，宝贝，过来
No... look. Hey! Baby. Come here. No.
宝贝，不要那样
Baby. No, don't do that.
回来爸爸这里
Come back to Daddy.
法兰琪，请不要那样做
Frankie, please, don't do that. Okay?
好吗，看着我，小乖 不要那样做
Look at me, honey. Don't do that.
法兰琪
Hey, Frankie.
法兰琪‥
Frankie!
梅芙
Maeve!
＂受限＂
宝贝，看着我
Hey, baby, look at me.
法兰琪，拜托住手‥
Frankie. Please stop!
拜托‥宝贝
Please, please... Frankie...
梅芙
Maeve!
＂已授权＂
我的天啊
Oh, my god.
宝贝
Hey, baby. Hey.
看着我
Hey, look at me.
你听得到我吗？
Can you hear... can you hear me?
宝贝？
Baby? Baby...
爸爸？
Daddy?
不对
No.
不对‥
No...
你好，梅芙
Hello, Maeve.
我期待这一刻很久了
I've been looking forward to this.
你被我教训得还不够吗？
Not yet tired of getting your arse kicked by me?
等等
Wait.
你不能走
You can't leave.
不会‥我不会走
No... I'm not gonna leave.
我再也不离开了，好吗？
Never again. Okay?
我保证
I promise.
我是说你不能离开这里
I mean, you can't leave here.
她要你留下
She wants you to stay.
你在说什么？
What are you talking about?
凯勒
Caleb?
你应该会发现‥
I think you'll find...
我和以前不太一样了
I'm not quite the man I used to be.
嘿
Hey.
他们也捉到妈妈了吗？
Did they get your mom too?
你知道她在哪里吗？ 她在不在这里？
Do you know where she is? Is she here?
没有，爸爸，她不在
No, Daddy. She's not.
但我跟妈妈 本来就不是海尔需要的人
But me and Mommy were never the ones Hale needed anyways.
她只需要你
All she needed was you...
天啊，好痛
Jesus. Shit.
你真以为玩具枪就能制服我？
Did you really think that toy gun was gonna stop me?
我们走，来吧‥
Let's go. Come on.
来吧
Come on.
你不是法兰琪
You're not Frankie.
这不用太久，爸爸
This won't take long, Daddy.
待续
双语合并：James丶xz
谢谢观赏